A Guide to the 8th Evacuation Hospital 1941-2011
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- Sandbags and the "shell" at Anzio, Italy 1944, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 13-047)
  A ward tent was located here during the siege
- Group around jeep ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 13-048)
  left to right: unidentified man, McNeel, Mark Clark, Stimson (pith helmet) 2 unidentified men, Drash, unidentified man
- Armored Italian vehicles ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 13-049)
  photo by Instituto Nazionale per le Relazioni Culturali con L'estero (National Institute for cultural Relations with Foreign Countries)
- 8th Evac nurses with helmets ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 13-050)
- Three men under a tree ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 13-051)
- Holsinger on left and unidentified man in front of jeeps on road ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 13-052)
- Unidentified men and women in front of hospital tent ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 13-053)
- 8th Evac at Pietramala, Italy, and the Futa Pass ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 13-054)
- Two men with a boy and a donkey ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 13-055)
- Men and boxes ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 4.75 x 3.25 (Box-folder 13-056)
- Group photo of men all unidentified except standing on far right: Johnsmeyer ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.5 x 4.5 (Box-folder 13-057)
- Three unidentified women in front of a tent ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 13-058)
- Unidentified man sitting on a cot ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 13-059)
- Two unidentified men standing by a tree-lined street ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 13-060)
- Inside X-ray tent, X-ray displayed 1944, PHOTO 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 13-061)
  Armed Forces Institute of Pathology Neg. No. C-44-579
- Two unidentified men in front of palm tree ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.25 x 4.5 (Box-folder 13-062)
- Unidentified men and women in camp ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 13-063)
- Tents with wooden sidewalk between them ND, PHOTOS 1-B&W 2.5 x 3, 1-B&W 2.5 x 3. 25 (Box-folder 13-064)
- Unidentified person with book outside tents ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 2.75 (Box-folder 13-065)
- Three men and one woman on boat, all unidentified ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 1.75 x 2.5 (Box-folder 13-066)
- Unidentified women under tree, tent half up ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.25 x 3.25 (Box-folder 13-067)
- Unidentified man and woman outside at table set for party, possibly Kirkman ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.25 x 3 (Box-folder 13-068)
- Tents ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 13-069)
- Unidentified men on trucks by train ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 1.75 x 2.5 (Box-folder 13-070)
- Tents, piles of wood, barrels ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 13-071)
- Two unidentified men by car ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 13-072)
- Operating tent ND, PHOTO B&W 8 x 10 (Box-folder 13-073)
  This photo shows the new braces which replaced the old tepee poles and also shows the instrument bundle stands that were stackable. The note on one photo is by Randal Luscombe and says, "Stand - made - 10 of them." Armed Forces Institute of Pathology photo
- Letter from Melvin C. Shaffer to Joan E. Klein with enclosed aerial photo of 8th Evac 1998 June 10, TLS 2 pp., PHOTO 1-B&W 8 x 10 (Box-folder 13-074)
  Shaffer writes about his camera surviving a 1000 foot fall from an airplane and its risky rescue. The photo shows the 8th Evac north of Naples in 1943 where the inspiration for the shower scene in the movie "MASH" occurred.
- Letter from Melvin C. Shaffer to Joan E. Klein with two enclosed photos 1998 June 10, TL 1 pg., PHOTO 1-B&W 4 x 5, 1-B&W 3.5 x 4.25 (Box-folder 13-075)
  Shaffer writes about filming a surgical procedure at the 8th Evac and includes photos that were used as a guide for the movie "MASH."
- Letter from Melvin C. Shaffer to Joan E. Klein with one enclosed photo of Shaffer and Snavely 1998 June 10, TLS 1 pg., PHOTO 1-B&W 8 x 10 (Box-folder 13-076)
- Letter from Melvin C. Shaffer to Joan E. Klein with two enclosed photos 1998 June 10, TLS 1 pg., PHOTOS 2-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 13-077)
  Shaffer writes about how to make a heater from a 500 pound bomb casing and encloses a photo of Shaffer on a cot in his tent and a photo of tents in the wet spring of 1945.
- Letter from Melvin C. Shaffer to Joan E. Klein with enclosed transparency 1998 June 10, TLS 1 pg., Kodachrome transparency 1-4 x 5 (Box-folder 13-078)
  The transparency is of the 8th Evac at Pietramala, Italy, and was made in the winter of 1944-45.
- Letter from Melvin C. Shaffer to Joan E. Klein with enclosed photo 1998 June 10, TLS 1 pg., PHOTO 1-B&W 8 x 10 (Box-folder 13-079)
  The photo shows from left to right: McNeel, Secretary of War Stimson (pith helmet), an unidentified man, and General Mark Clark and was taken in September 1944.
- Letter from Melvin C. Shaffer to Joan E. Klein with two enclosed photos 1998 June 10, TL 1 pg., PHOTOS 2-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 13-080)
  The photos show tents, patients, and military personnel at the 8th Evac's Lake Garda location in the summer of 1945.
- Letter from Melvin C. Shaffer to Joan E. Klein with enclosed photo 1998 June 10, TLS 1 pg., PHOTO 1-B&W 8 x 10 (Box-folder 13-081)
  The photo is of the area near the 8th Evac camp at Pietramala in the winter of 1944-45 and shows the Brenner Pass. Senator Bob Dole was severely wounded here.
- Officers of the 8th Evac at the Italian Consulate, Casablanca 1942 December, PHOTOS 1-B&W 5 x 7, 2-B&W 7 x 9.25, 1-B&W 8 x 10, 2-B&W 9 x 11.5, 1 negative (Box-folder 13-082)
  Top row: 1st Lts. Low, Mapp, Miller, Monin, Hairfield, Driscoll, Mayo, Mulford, Smith, Northrup, Casscells, Laird, W., Ross, Morris, Kinkoff, Scarborough; Third row: Capts. Grim, Waddell, Shearburn, Gillespie, Beck, Haley, Suhling, Leavell, Windham, Payne, Marshall, Culbertson, L., Guerrant, Culbertson, J., Thornton, Bell, Den; 2nd row: Majs. Holsinger, Hill, Laird, E., Holmboe, Lt. Cols. Blackford, Putnam, Drash, Majs. McNeel, Siersema, Kinser, LeBauer, Winthrop; bottom row: 2nd Lts. Lynch, Jenkins, 1st Lts. Churchill, Blessing, 2nd Lts. Snavely, Weller, Murrian
- Letter from Melvin C. Shaffer to Joan E. Klein with two enclosed photos 1998 June 10, TL 1 pg., PHOTOS 2-B&W 8 x 10, 1 negative (Box-folder 13-083)
  The photo is of the 8th Evac staff in the summer of 1944.
- Personal recollections of the 8th Evac by John L. Guerrant 2000 June 25, TLS 2 pp. (Box-folder 13-084)
  This recollection was used for the "8th Evacuation Hospital: The University of Virginia in World War II" web site.
- Personal recollections of the 8th Evac by William P. Snavely ND, 2 TD 6 pp. (Box-folder 13-085)
- Personal Reflections of the 8th Evac Hospital and Post War personal History of Beverley D. Tucker, Jr. by Beverley D. Tucker, Jr., and letter from Beverley D. Tucker to Janet Pearson 2000 November 3, ALS, 3 TD, 1 envelope, 12 pp. (Box-folder 13-086)
- Letter from Alice Huffman Bugel to Anne regarding her personal recollections of the 8th Evac ND, TL, 1 envelope, 1 memorex disk containing history letter, 6 pp. (Box-folder 13-087)
- 8th Evac Hospital addresses - 1995 1995, 1 TD with AN, 1 photocopy TD with AN, 14 pp. (Box-folder 13-088)
  These are updated copies of the 1990 address list. Autograph notes on the original are from 1995. The photocopy includes autograph notes from 2000. Names marked "returned" refer to a mailing sent in 2000.
- Letter from John Guerrant to Former Members of the 8th Evacuation Hospital Unit 2000 July 11, 2 ALS, photocopy ALS, photocopy TLS, 1 envelope, 5 pp. (Box-folder 13-089)
  Guerrant solicits personal recollections for the "8th Evacuation Hospital: The University of Virginia in World War II" web site.
- Ear, eye, nose, throat clinic tent ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 14-001)
- Moving day leaving Caserta: nurses with gear and loading truck 1943 October, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7, 1-B&W 8 x 10 (Box-folder 14-002)
- Moving day: trucks loaded with soldiers on way to Marreketch (Marrakech, Morocco?) ND, PHOTOS 1-B&W 3.75 x 5, 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 14-003)
- Monin on top of truck in convoy ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 14-004)
- McKoan observing pitching of tents, man on pole for electricity ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 14-005)
- 8th Evac camp at Anfa Hill, Casablanca, Morocco 1943 June, PHOTO 1-B&W 8.25 x 10 (Box-folder 14-006)
  8th Evac camp was across the street from the Anfa Hotel where Roosevelt, Stalin and Churchill met.
- Snow by tents in Pietramala, Italy ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 14-007)
- Original nurses of the 8th Evac in uniform at a cocktail party at the Pantops 1942, PHOTO 1-B&W 8 x 10 (Box-folder 14-008)
- 8th Evac camp at Anfa Hill, Casablanca, Morocco 1943 Spring, PHOTO 1-B&W 8 x 10 (Box-folder 14-009)
- Tents in olive grove, nurses' and officers' row, near Florence, Italy 1944, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 14-010)
- Reynold Siersema standing in front of jeep preparing for pitching tents ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 14-011)
- Moving day: trucks driving through town ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 14-012)
  Holsinger bottom right with pipe
- Men sitting inside at a table ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.5 x 5 (Box-folder 14-013)
  left to right: Kirkman, Blackford, two unidentified men
- Jefferson Day celebration ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 14-014)
  left to right: Blackford, Wray, Michie, Laird at table
- Mark Clark and King George VI ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 14-015)
  Clark is tall man in center, King George is 2nd from the right, others are unidentified
- Left to right: Weller, Drash and Martin at Martin's promotion to "field clerk" ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 14-016)
- Kirkman pouring a drink ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 14-017)
- Left to right: Holmboe, Drash, Blackford standing 1944 September, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 14-018)
- William Laird conducting a service ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 14-019)
- Ned Waddell shining shoes ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 14-020)
- Dempsey and Mallahan outside tent at Anfa Hill, Casablanca 1943, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.25 x 4.75 (Box-folder 14-021)
- Six unidentified enlisted men ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.25 x 4.5 (Box-folder 14-022)
- Roy Waller peering out of tent in long johns ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.75 (Box-folder 14-023)
- Unidentified man standing next to Dempsey who is on the right ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 14-024)
- Clare Booth Luce visits a wounded patient at Pietramala, Italy 1944 December 17, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 14-025)
- Left to right: Blackford, unidentified man, Irving Berlin and Holmboe ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 14-026)
- Boxer Joe Lewis visits the 8th Evac, Drash is second from left ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 14-027)
- Operating room in use 1944, PHOTO 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 14-028)
  Armed Forces Institute of Pathology Neg. No. 5-44-100394
- Blood bank refrigerator 1944, PHOTO 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 14-029)
  Armed Forces Institute of Pathology Neg. No. 5-44-589
- Ward tents at Capua, Italy ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 14-030)
- Prefabricated building used as a ward at the 8th Evac, Pietramala, Italy 1945 January 13, PHOTO 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 14-031)
  One end of the building sets several feet off the ground on stilts and is anchored to the ground by steel cables. Armed Forces Institute of Pathology Neg. No. 5/MM-45-772
- Angie Brusatto at Central Surgical Supply table 1944, PHOTO 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 14-032)
  Armed Forces Institute of Pathology Neg. No. C--44-556
- Clare Booth Luce visits a wounded soldier, Fred L. Heuson at the 8th Evac, Pietramala, Italy 1945 March 21, PHOTO 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 14-033)
  Armed Forces Institute of Pathology 5/MM-45-4982
- Headquarters Group, Tucker standing far right, rest unidentified ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5.5 x 8.5 (Box-folder 14-034)
- Staige Blackford ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 8 x 10 (Box-folder 14-035)
- Anfa Hotel, Casablanca, Morocco ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.75 (Box-folder 14-036)
- North African woman ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 4.25 (Box-folder 14-037)
- Distinguished visitors: Stimson second from far right, Clark is far right ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 14-038)
- Serving mess in ward tent ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 8 x 10 (Box-folder 14-039)
  This photo shows the center portion of a standard ward.
- North African man ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 4.25 (Box-folder 14-040)
- North African man with horse and cart ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 4.25 (Box-folder 14-041)
- North African scene with man on burro ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 4.25 (Box-folder 14-042)
- "The Stars and Stripes," Mediterranean vol. 1. no. 243. "Nazi Armies in Italy Surrender" 1945 May 3, newspaper, 8 pp. (Box-folder 14-043)
- RUTH BEERY'S SCRAPBOOK 1942-1945, Artifact: Scrapbook includes medals, dogtags, coins, patches, bars, newspaper clippings, letters, citations, postcards, and photographs. (Box-folder 15-000)
  Scrapbook photographs include those of Pageland, South Carolina; Halloran General Hospital, Staten Island, New York; Casablanca; Cairo; Switzerland; Italy: Caserta, Teano, Carinola, Cellole, Cecina, Anzio, Le Ferriero, Pietramala, Po River, Pisa, Venice, Gardone, and Milan; and 1950 reunion
- Fifth Army commendation for the 8th Evac 1944, 2 TD, 1 TDS 3 pp. (Box-folder 16-001)
  Commendation is for meritorious service during January 1944
- Citation for meritorious service of the 8th Evac, April and May, 1945 1945 September 10, 6 TD, 6 pp. (Box-folder 16-002)
- Elizabeth Harlin's membership card ND, 1 TCS 1 pg. (Box-folder 16-003)
  Alumnae Association of the Training School for Nurses of the Garfield memorial Hospital, Washington D.C.
- Letter from Mrs. Mark Temple to E. C. Drash 1944 May 29, 1 TLS, 1 pg. (Box-folder 16-004)
  Letter concerns Red Cross surgical dressings sent to the 8th Evac
- "Active Duty Calls Received By Two In Hospital Unit" ND, 1 newspaper clipping, 1 pg. (Box-folder 16-005)
  Drash and Shearburn ordered to report for duty
- "Unit Well Versed in Advancements Since World War" and "Hospital Medical Unit Members Enroute Today" 1942 July 1, 1 newspaper clippings, 2 pp. (Box-folder 16-006)
- Men walking outside tents ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 16-007)
- 8th Evac operating tent in use ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 16-008)
  operating tent had 8 operating tables and 2 sterile supply tables
- Churchill's villa in Casablanca on Anfa Hill 1943 February, PHOTO 1-B&W 7 x 9.25 (Box-folder 16-009)
- President Roosevelt's villa in Casablanca on Anfa Hill 1943 February, PHOTO 1-B&W 7 x 9.25 (Box-folder 16-010)
- Tents ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.25 x 3.5 (Box-folder 16-011)
- Tents ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 16-012)
- Jeeps ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.25 x 3.25 (Box-folder 16-013)
- Man and woman ladling drink in front of tent ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.25 x 3 (Box-folder 16-014)
- Unidentified group of 8 men ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 1.75 x 2.25 (Box-folder 16-015)
- Two unidentified women in front of hanging laundry and tents ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2 x 2.75 (Box-folder 16-016)
- Unidentified men and women with straw in front of tents ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2 x 2.75 (Box-folder 16-017)
- Signpost on city street with miles to New York, Washington, Berlin, and Tokyo ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 16-018)
- Captain Wiel and Elizabeth Harlin, directors of the Home for Convalescing Nurses ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 16-019)
- Left to right: Captain Wiel, unidentified woman, and Elizabeth Harlin ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 16-020)
  Wiel and Harlin were directors of the Home for Convalescing Nurses
- Nurses lined up for review pre 1945 January 5, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 16-021)
- Unidentified people on ship ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 16-022)
- Tents ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 1.75 x 2.5 (Box-folder 16-023)
- Tents ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 1.75 x 2.5 (Box-folder 16-024)
- Oxen pulling a loaded cart in front of tents ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 2.75 (Box-folder 16-025)
- Two unidentified men near tables set up with food in front of tents ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3 (Box-folder 16-026)
- People in front of tents ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.25 (Box-folder 16-027)
  Probably Drash and Harlin on right
- Ten seated unidentified women ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 16-028)
- Men and nurses on board ship returning to the U.S. from Naples, Italy 1945 November, PHOTO STRIP with 4 images, 1-B&W 1.25 x 7.25 (Box-folder 16-029)
  2nd, 3rd, and 4th photos show nurses Hornbarger (on left) and Dorothy Sandridge (on right). Ruth Beery is in front in the 2nd photo.
- Truck carrying a boat on curving road ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 4.75 x 7 (Box-folder 16-030)
  Notation on back: "Una difficile curva in Montagna."
- Small boats in water carrying helmeted servicemen ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7.25 (Box-folder 16-031)
  Notation on back: ISTITUTO NAZIONALS PER LE RELAZIONI CULTURALI CON L'ESTERO. ROMA - Via Quattro Fontane 20, SERVIZIO FOTOGRAFICO, 12328 - Battelli armati dell'Armata Italiana in Russia in perlustrazione lungo un corso d'acqua sul fronte orientale.
- Ship in water ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7.25 (Box-folder 16-032)
  Notation on back: ISTITUTO NAZIONALS PER LE RELAZIONI CULTURALI CON L'ESTERO. ROMA - Via Quattro Fontane 20, SERVIZIO FOTOGRAFICO, 12057 - Una nave nemica centrata dal siluro di un sommergibile italiano operante nell'Atlantico mentre affonda lentamente.
- Heavily armored Soviet train that fell into the hand of Italian troops ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7.25 (Box-folder 16-033)
  Notation on back: ISTITUTO NAZIONALS PER LE RELAZIONI CULTURALI CON L'ESTERO. ROMA - Via Quattro Fontane 20, SERVIZIO FOTOGRAFICO, 11423 - Treno blindato sovietico caduto intatto nelle mani delle truppe italiane nell'ansa del Don.
- Line of trucks apparently for troop transport 1942 June 21, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7.25 (Box-folder 16-034)
  Notation on back: ISTITUTO NAZIONALS LUCE = ROMA 21/6/42 XX RG. 6093, Tobruch e il suo porto, [?] dalle truppe italiane e germaniche
- Three women, middle is Elizabeth Harlin ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 16-035)
  Notation on back: Fiosole
- Hitler and Mussolini ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 7.5 x 11.75 (Box-folder 16-036)
- Nurses and patients in tent ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3 (Box-folder 16-037)
  Notation on back: Interior of the post-operative tent
- Patients and cots in tent ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3 (Box-folder 16-038)
  Notation on back: Interior of post-operative tent
- Cattle and tin shacks ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 16-039)
- Nonmilitary women in front of nonmilitary tent ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 16-040)
- Loaded camel and man on a burro ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 16-041)
- Drash, Kinkopf, unidentified man, and Snavely with the plaque received for meritorious service 1944, PHOTO 1-B&W 8 x 10 (Box-folder 16-042)
  Nurses, patients and tents in the background
- Kirkman holding a drink ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.25 x 3.25 (Box-folder 16-043)
- Nurse in shower ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3 (Box-folder 16-044)
- Three people behind towels sitting on a bench or latrine ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3 (Box-folder 16-045)
- Paths in deep snow ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.25 x 3 (Box-folder 16-046)
- Tents in snow ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.25 x 3 (Box-folder 16-047)
- Rutted toad with hospital tents in background ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.25 x 3 (Box-folder 16-048)
- Woman getting liquid from barrel container ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.25 x 3 (Box-folder 16-049)
- Tents in snow ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.25 x 3 (Box-folder 16-050)
- Unidentified people on a bench ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 1.75 x 2.5 (Box-folder 16-051)
- Unidentified person sitting outside on a stool ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2 x 2.75 (Box-folder 16-052)
- Tents ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 16-053)
- Ship in port ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 16-054)
- Buildings on a hill ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.75 x 4 (Box-folder 16-055)
- Military personnel by vehicle ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 16-056)
- Military personnel, tents, jeeps; Driscoll on far right ND, PHOTOS 2-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 16-057)
- Helmeted Elizabeth Harlin in front of tent ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.25 x 4.5 (Box-folder 16-058)
- Nurse and tents, Pageland, S. C. 1942 July-August, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3 (Box-folder 16-059)
- Tents, Pageland, S. C. 1942 July-August, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3 (Box-folder 16-060)
- Tents, Pageland, S. C. 1942 July-August, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3 (Box-folder 16-061)
- Ten women in front of tents, Pageland, S. C. 1942 July-August, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3 (Box-folder 16-062)
  Beery in checkered dress
- Nurse in front of tent, Pageland, S. C. 1942 July-August, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3 (Box-folder 16-063)
- Nurse in front of tent, Pageland, S. C. 1942 July-August, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3 (Box-folder 16-064)
- Elizabeth Harlin by tent, Pageland, S. C. 1942 July-August, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 16-065)
- Elizabeth Harlin inside tent, Pageland, S. C. 1942 July-August, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 16-066)
- Woman sitting on steps, probably of nurses' quarters, Pageland, S. C. 1942 July-August, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 16-067)
- three women in tent, Pageland, S. C. 1942 July-August, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 16-068)
- Women with luggage sitting on steps, probably of nurses' quarters, Pageland, S. C. 1942 July-August, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 16-069)
- Tent ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 16-070)
  Notation on back of photo: showers - Rockingham, N. C.
- Looking down on 8th Evac at Pietramala, Italy ND, PHOTO with OVERLAY 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 16-071)
  Notation on back: "Alumni News: April 1963, page 9
- Surgeons operating 1944, PHOTO with OVERLAY 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 16-072)
  Armed Forces Institute of Pathology Neg. No. C-44-557, Notation on back: "Alumni News: April 1963, page 9
- Clare booth Luce at Pietramala, Italy 1944 December 17, PHOTOS 2-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 16-073)
- Servicemen at Pietramala, Italy 1944-45, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 16-074)
- Servicemen and jeep at Pietramala, Italy 1944, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.25 x 2.75 (Box-folder 16-075)
- Looking down on the 8th Evac tents at Pietramala, Italy, no snow ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.5 x 5 (Box-folder 16-076)
- Marie Glavin and Major Chamberlain on their wedding day 1944 April 11, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 16-077)
- Reunion pre 1980, PHOTO 1-B&W 8 x 10 (Box-folder 16-078)
  Left to right: Elizabeth Harlin Drash, Jane Anderson, 2 unidentified women, e. Cato Drash, unidentified woman
- Operating room 1944, PHOTO 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 16-079)
  Armed Forces Institute of Pathology Neg. No. C-44-593
- Washing machine, possibly for sterilizing supplies for operating room 1944, PHOTO 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 16-080)
  Armed Forces Institute of Pathology Neg. No. C-44-565
- Emptying a bedpan 1944, PHOTO 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 16-081)
  Armed Forces Institute of Pathology Neg. No. C-44-567
- Ward tents blown down by wind, not 8th Evac but nearby ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 16-082)
- Men sawing wood for heating tents of army personnel 1944, PHOTO 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 16-083)
- Water truck and water tank 1944, PHOTO 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 16-084)
  Armed Forces Institute of Pathology Neg. No. C-44-571
- Nurses standing in lines ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 16-085)
- Jefferson Day celebration 1944 April 13, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 16-086)
  from left to right: Wray, Blackford, Michie, William Laird
- Women ironing in tent ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 16-087)
  Notation on back: Setting up operating room supplies. Italian women
- Washing machines and woman in tent ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 4.25 x 5.25 (Box-folder 16-088)
  Notation on back: Washing operating room supplies
- Left to right: Holmboe, Drash, and Blackford ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 4 (Box-folder 16-089)
- The erection of a tent with a frame designed in part by Randal Luscombe ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 16-090)
  Randal Luscombe or Maurice LeBauer supervises the erection
- Moving day ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 16-091)
  Left to right: Sue Hornbarger, Elizabeth Wiseman, Jane Anderson, civilian, unidentified people
- People sitting 1943, PHOTOS 2-B&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 16-092)
  McKoan facing nurse (Ruth Beery?) with Blackford behind nurse
- ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 16-093)